Edem Alloh

35 Elephant Lane, Rotherhithe, SE16 4JD | 07788 240 711 | info@edemalloh.com | http://edemalloh.com

Personal Summary

A hard-working, motivated & determined web developer, specializing in front end technologies. With experience working in teams and solo, to achieve goals & deliver functionality within set deadlines. Able to deliver effectively & efficiently under pressure.

Experience

FRONT END DEVELOPER | CHEIL | AUGUST 2016 - Present

- Development & maintenance of the Samsung UK & IE website, using:
 - o HTML
 - o CSS & SCSS
 - o IS (& jQuery)
 - Handlebars
 - o Gulp
- Creation & maintenance of page templates using AEM
- Interaction with clients to gain requirements/feedback on website builds
- Worked on pages that gained 100s of 1000s of monthly traffic

FRONT END DEVELOPER | CUESONGS | FEBRUARY 2015 - MAY 2016

- Design & development of an e-commerce website, using:
 - HTML & CSS (+ SCSS)
 - o jQuery (+ JS)
 - Handlebars
 - Gulp for building distributables (bundling / optimization)
- Creation of responsive HTML email templates for use with the core platform
- Partial usage of PHP (Blade) for bug fixing of API and feature development
- Management of the blog platform, which included:
 - Designing layouts and implementing articles written by the editorial team
 - Lead development of an editorial CMS to allow for management of static content within the site
- Interviewing/surveying to gain feedback for future functionalities to add to the UX and functionality development for the core platform
- Reporting to the CTO on newly completed features/bug fixing as well as planning future tasks for completion

GRAPHIC DESIGNER | SELF EMPLOYED | JANUARY 2009 - PRESENT

- Research & image sourcing (sometimes using own photography) for given brief/theme
- Creating rough drafts based on initial ideas
 - o Flyers
 - o Digital Album Artwork
 - 12" Vinyl Sleeves/Labels

- Modifying/revising the rough draft based on client feedback
- Providing final deliverables for print

Education

BSC - COMPUTER SCIENCE | SEPTEMBER 2011 - JUNE 2014 | BRUNEL UNIVERSITY

- Completed a final year project which included analysis of codebases/modification of Eclipse plug-ins to educate first year Computer Science students on best practices of coding, coding conventions & avoiding bad code smells > Participation in group projects which included:
 - Developing an Android app (using Java) which allowed citizens to report local issues in their council/borough
 - Creating a website (using HTML, CSS & JS) which educated first year Computer Science students about placement schemes
- Creation of an educational card game (using the XNA framework C++) which helped students practice conversion of decimal to binary, hexadecimal & two's complement
- Partial learning & understanding of Python, project management, usability & networking protocols

3 A*-B A LEVELS (COMPUTING, BUSINESS STUDIES & PHOTOGRAPHY) 8 A-C GCSES (INCLUDING MATHS & ENGLISH)

Technical Skills

- Strong knowledge of HTML (knowledge of BEM naming syntax for classes)
- Strong knowledge of CSS/SCSS
- · jQuery/JS
- · Handlebars
- · Gulp
- · Git/Gitflow
- · Experience with PHP (using the Laravel framework)
- · Experience with SQL
- · Knowledge of Photoshop
- · Experience with Java & C++

Interests

My main hobby is music production (specializing in Drum & Bass/Jungle). I've been producing for just 7 years and have had songs released on various Drum & Bass record labels. I've also had some of my songs played in clubs worldwide (as well as playing DJ sets in clubs across the UK) & on radio stations like BBC 1Xtra, Kiss FM, Rinse FM & NTS Radio, by a variety of DJs/other producers.